<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Financing malaria control in Mozambique</title>
    <description>Private-sector foreign financing of malaria control and eradication: investigating preferences and quantifying its benefits and costs</description>
    <link>joebrew.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="joebrew.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 23:27:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 23:27:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Please give me your data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's me, Pepe, from Swashbuckle.  We exchanged a few emails a couple months ago.  And then I exchanged some, by myself.  Well, I sent them to you, but you never wrote back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks passed, then the weeks became fortnights (I just learned that word, isn't it cool, it makes me sound British, doesn't it!?), then the fortnights (awesome word!) became months. No reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I occasionally would open some of the emails I had sent you, to see if perhaps I had said something offensive, but nope, they were pretty vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Why won't you just give me your data?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You sounded so excited on the phone. You were like &quot;yeah, let's do this, cool!&quot; and I was like &quot;alright, yeah, great!&quot;  Such positive energy, man!  I was so pumped after our call that I kicked a baby!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Don't worry, it wasn't some stranger's baby.  This was a baby that's been hanging around my house for a while, acting weird and stuff.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/data_please/data_please_2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;I can't really think of any way in which this photo is relevant&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Imagine, you and me, playing the data-for-in-kind-analysis marimba together, forever.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so, what happened?  I mean, did you meet someone else to whom you're gonna give your data?  Am I being overbearing?  Underbearing?  Do you want me to better balance my bearing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Do you want to talk about it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen, I get it.  These things happen.  Sometimes people offer data, and then they act like big old jerks.  C'est la vie, right?  No big deal.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/data_please/data_please_3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;So many photos in this post&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Don’t worry, I’ll never hang you out to dry.  (Get it?  Cause the photo…)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, do you think we could, you know, just have a cup of coffee together and talk about it?  I know you're really busy and stuff, but I just want some closure, you know?  I mean if you're really busy, it's okay, that's fine, no worries.  Yeah, I'm pretty busy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>joebrew.github.io/2015/11/10/data_please/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">joebrew.github.io/2015/11/10/data_please/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The elevator pitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s how one might describe this project in &amp;lt; 1 minute (ie, when making a pitch on an elevator):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malaria is costly to business in Mozambique, particularly the many large foreign direct investments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But investors and business leaders are hesitant to invest in controlling malara because they’re not sure sure what the return on that investment will be, nor do they understand which interventions will be accepted by workers and their families.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re trying to quantify the economics benefits of malaria control interventions from a business-owner’s or investor’s standpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re trying to qualify community and individual preferences about malaria control.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we do both of those things well, our work will hopefully facilitate the natural and organic flow of resources to where it is most needed and will be most effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 08:50:36 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>joebrew.github.io/none/2015/09/24/elevator_pitch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">joebrew.github.io/none/2015/09/24/elevator_pitch/</guid>
        
        
        <category>none</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project sketch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, government resources are the primary source of funding for controlling malaria. One reason why the private sector plays only a tertiary role is that the costs of malaria control are known, whereas its benefits are difficult to quantify. It stands to reason, however, that reducing the burden of malaria in endemic areas would result in higher worker output and greater productivity. If these economic benefits are quantified, the flow of private investment to malaria control will increase in cases in which it is beneficial to a company’s bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to quantify the economic benefits of malaria control for consumption by potential foreign investors, better understanding is needed both of (a) which methods are most acceptable by local populations, (b) the cost-effectivity and cost-utility of malaria control methods in regards to their impact on worker productivity and (c) the landscape of potential economic beneficiaries of malaria control.  This project aims to address the above three gaps in knowledge, producing public-facing estimates and toolkits for the maximization of profit and public health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 09:51:23 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>joebrew.github.io/none/2015/09/22/sketch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">joebrew.github.io/none/2015/09/22/sketch/</guid>
        
        
        <category>none</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
